Ross Franey (he/him)

Software Engineer

Profile

Software Engineer for Qualtrics, with 2.5 years of professional experience.

Graduated top of class in Dublin City University with a 1st Class Honours.

I pride myself in having an in-depth understanding of computer science fundamentals, data structures and algorithms, clean coding principals and scalable architecture.

Education

Ba. Software Engineering, Dublin City University

September 2015 — June 2018

- · 1st Class Honor
- · Graduated top of class
- · Student Ambassador

Employment History

Software Engineer at Qualtrics, Dublin

August 2018 — Present

- Scope and deliver complex, varied projects as the sole engineer, for a number of global clients such as Google, L'Oreal, HSBC and Adidas.
- Work on a large scale SMS distribution product sending 4 million weekly messages, on which I have added a 700% performance increase and an improved queuing system.
- Received internal award for developing "Survey as Code" System, allowing users to manage surveys through Git.
- Designed and delivered a data privacy API for Adidas.
- Received 2 quarterly "exceeds expectations" performance ratings.

Software Engineer Intern at Cellusys, Dublin

March 2017 — September 2017

- Serving telecom clients in Java / Clojure based projects
- Delivered feature to distinguish between Arabic / Non-Arabic messages
- Gained experience with Puppet / Docker / Jenkins

Personal Projects

Machine learning trading platform (Python Web & Android App)

Android App - Motion Detection Security System

Asynchronous Messenger Chat Applet

Please visit https://rossfraney.github.io/Ross-Franey/ for more information.

■ References

References available upon request

Details

ross.franey3@mail.dcu.ie

Links

Profile & Project Website Linkedin

Skills

Python, PHP, NodeJS, Java, Javascript, React

AWS Lambda, S3, DynamoDB

Scoping & System Design

Technical Writing / Design Documentation

Databases (MongoDB, SQL, DynamoDB)

Data Structures & Algorithms

Hobbies

Coding challenges / contests Volunteer with refugee groups Personal finance, investing Sports